A taxi driver was driving...
Manejaba un taxista...
and a sleepy deaf person rushed out,
y una somnolienta persona sorda se afanó,
because they were late for an appointment.
porque llegaba tarde a su cita.
They went down the stairs,
Bajó las escaleras,
called an Uber,
pidió un Uber,
and the cab showed up.
y llegó el taxi.
They were putting their suitcase in the car,
Iba subiendo su maleta al auto,
and the driver asked where they were going.
y el taxista le preguntó a dónde iba.
The deaf person closed the door and said:
El sordo cerró la puerta y dijo:
Oh sorry, I'm deaf!
¡Ay perdón, soy sordo!
The driver: Where are you going?
El taxista: A dónde vas?
The deaf person motioned to keep going straight.
El sordo le indicó que siguiese derecho.
The driver drove straight
El taxista condujo derecho
and didn't know what to do with their deaf passenger.
y no sabía qué hacer con su pasajero sordo.
They kept glancing in the rearview mirror and kept driving...
Lo veía por el retrovisor y continuaba manejando...
"Now turn left"
"Ahora a la izquierda"
"OK, left"
"OK, a la izquierda"
They kept driving
Seguía manejando
and stopped at the red light.
y se detuvo en el semáforo con la luz roja.
They waited for people to cross.
Esperó a que las personas pasarán.
The deaf person was very anxious
El sordo estaba muy inquieto
because it was already late.
porque ya era tarde.
Let's go please, I'm really late!
¡Vámonos por favor, es my tarde!
"Wait, it's red"
"Espere que está en rojo"
Let's go please!
¡Vámonos por favor!
The driver obeyed
El taxista obedeció
and ran the red light.
y se pasó el rojo.
The passenger, really worried about being late...
El pasajero bien preocupado por la tardanza...
"Hey, if you hit a red light, ignore it"
"Oye, si te toca una luz roja, no le hagas caso"
"Just keep going, because it's really late"
"Tú continúa, porque ya es muy tarde"
Then a patrol car showed up
En eso aparece una patrulla
and told them to pull over.
y le dijo que se orillara.
They pulled over and said: Hey, what happened?
Se orilló y le dijo: ¿Oiga, que pasó?
"You ran a red light"
"Se pasó la luz roja"
"Oh yeah, sorry, my passenger is deaf"
"Ah sí, disculpe, mi pasajero es sordo"
They spoke and sure enough, the deaf person couldn't hear them.
Le habló y en efecto, la persona sorda no le escuchaba.
"All right,
"Bueno, está bien,
you can pay me off"
le daré una mordida"
They paid up and kept driving.
Se la dio y continuó conduciendo.
The deaf person was desperate
La persona sorda ya estaba desesperada
and asked to switch seats.
y le pidió que cambiaran de lugar.
The driver agreed and now the deaf person was driving.
El chofer aceptó y ahora el sordo manejaba.
And they blew through every red light.
Y se pasaba todas las luces rojas.
The driver was stunned that they ran the lights.
El chofer estaba sorprendido de que se saltara los altos.
A cop spotted them
Un policía los vio
and followed them for a while.
y los siguió un rato.
And said: Pull over!
Y le dijo: ¡Oríllese!
So they pulled over.
Y se orilló.
What happened?
¿Qué pasó?
"Oh, I'm deaf, sorry"
"Ay, yo soy sordo, disculpe"
And the officer: You're fine, go ahead.
Y el policía: Está bien, continúe.
The shocked driver: Just because they're deaf!
El chofer sorprendido: ¡Solo porque es sordo!
They stopped me a minute ago and I had to pay a bribe!
¡Hace un rato me detuvieron y tuve que dar mordida!
I'll learn!
¡Aprenderé!
The deaf person got to their destination, paid the driver, and left.
El sordo llegó a su destino, pagó al chofer y se fue.
The driver learned from the experience.
Aprendió el chofer de su experiencia.
They picked up another fare and had to get somewhere fast.
Subíó otro pasaje y tenía que llegar rápido a su destino.
They remembered what happened with their deaf passenger.
Recordó la experiencia de su pasajero sordo.
They took off, drove, and ran the lights.
Arrancó, condujo y se pasó los altos.
A cop pulled them over and they said: I'm deaf!
Un policía le detuvo y le dijo: ¡Yo soy sordo!
The officer said: OK, wait.
El policía le dijo: OK, espere.
They went and got a manual and started signing to them.
Fue por un manual y le empezó a decir con señas.
And the stunned driver: What?
Y el chófer sorprendido: ¿Qué?
"Sorry, talk to me"
"Perdón, hábleme"
And that's how the officer realized they could hear.
Y así fue como el policía se percató de que era oyente.